It has happened that
if you have also changed a second hand vehicle
and the
name of the new owner has been transferred in its registration certificate, then it
is necessary for you to enter the name of the new owner in the insurance policy within a certain period of time. It is
necessary to get the name of the new owner verified. If
you do not enter the name of the new owner in the insurance policy within 14 days, then the
insurance company can also reject your claim. So
friends, what documents will we need to
print the poster of the name of the new owner in the insurance policy,
how much fee is charged for it, what is its process,
I will tell you this in today's video.
I am Nitin Pal with you, you are watching
Insurance Group, so friends, let me take
you directly to my computer
screen where I will tell you in detail which
documents will be required, what will be
its fee and what will be its
decision so that you can get the
name of the new owner correct in the insurance policy, we
also call it endorsement, so my friends, without wasting any time,
I have taken you
on my computer screen, which documents will be required to get the insurance policy registered in the
name of the new owner,
in today's video I am going to
tell you this.  So first of all
we will need the registration certificate
which should have been transferred in the name of the new person in
whose name we are going to
transfer the insurance policy. The
first requirement is that the
registration certificate of the vehicle should have already been transferred in his name.
Secondly
we will need proposals for proposal. The proposal for sign will be done by the
new person in whose name the
registration certificate has been recently made
and in whose name the insurance policy is going to be
transferred. The proposal form will be
signed there. Settings
will be recruited. The proposal for there is a requirement of
request letter from wire. So the person in whose
name we are going to get the insurance policy transferred
and the RC has already been
transferred, he will
write a request letter to the insurance company that
I have purchased this vehicle from this person
and its insurance policy has already been done
from your office and this
insurance policy should be transferred in my name
because I have also
purchased this yesterday and its RC has been transferred in my name.
In that replacement letter
you have to write a simple word like this. So
friends fourth  The requirement is a request
letter from the owner, so friends, the person who has
sold the vehicle will
give a request letter to the insurance company that I have
sold my vehicle to this owner and the
insurance policy should be transferred in that name, I do
not have any option in that
because RC 2 has been transferred online in his name,
so friends, a
request letter will also be sent from the saver's side, so
friends, the fifth requirement is the
insurance policy of his vehicle, that we are going to
transfer the insurance policy in the name of the owner, that
we will have to attach a copy of the insurance policy of that vehicle
with it, so friends, these are the total
five documents which we mainly need to
transfer any old insurance policy to a new name, so
friends, along with this, you
also have a glass of no claim bonus, so friends, the no
claim bonus is of the previous owner,
when you are getting an insurance policy
transferred in the name of a new owner, then the
no claim bonus in the previous insurance policy is applicable to the
new owner.  You have to
make a deposit in the insurance company,
you can see in your insurance policy
whether it is 20%, 1957 or
f-35
500 or 50%, whatever it is,
you will have to deposit it in the insurance office,
after that it will be transferred in your insurance policy
name, after that friends let's
talk about the loot fee, the transfer fee is
normally ₹40 and
GST is levied on it which totals to ₹9, the
total transfer fee is ₹90, if there is
no claim bonus in the previous insurance policy then
your insurance
policy will be transferred for ₹15 and if there was a no claim
bonus in the previous insurance policy, the
amount of no claim bonus plus the
transfer fee, by adding these two together this amount will be enough,
after depositing it in your insurance office the insurance policy will be transferred in the name of New York,
now let's talk further about the
time period, so friends, after
15 days of RC transfer we can get the insurance policy done in our name
without any inspection, so
friends because this one
I have been asked many times that if
we do not get the insurance policy transferred within 14 days,
then will the insurance policy
never be transferred in your name? So, this is
not the case, so friends, here I
want to make it clear to you that under the
VAT for TDS, if you request the insurance company to
transfer the insurance policy in the name of the minimum, then
even without inspection, your insurance
policy will be transferred to your new name
and if you apply to transfer the insurance policy after 14 days, then
your vehicle will be
affected and after that fracture,
your vehicle will be transferred in the name, so
friends, these are the conditions, these are the
terminations, which I am telling you in the last also,
before this I have told you five
documents, by combining those five documents
and by filling these condition scores fully,
you can get the insurance policy transferred in the name of the ninth person,
which is very important
if the name in your registration certificate is
different and the name in the insurance policy is
different and if you also get a stamped tomorrow, then the
insurance  The company
is not liable to pay your claim
till the day the registration certificate is transferred in your name. If
you do not mention the insurance policy and registration
certificate separately,
but
if you do not mention the insurance policy and your
registration certificate separately, then the
insurance company will not mention
which documents are required to register the owner's name in this policy
and how much is the fee and have completed it, then do
tell me how you liked today's video and if you have any doubt related to this video
or if you have any, then you
can also ask me, so friends, if you are a
first time champion, please
subscribe to my channel, like it and while
subscribing to share, do not miss the bell icon button at all
so that you can get the notification of my upcoming videos
first on your mobile. So
friends, that is all for today, we will
meet soon with a new video with more topics. Jai Hind, Jai Bharat